PROFILE

Henry Jones Full Stack Web Developer popstar0126@gmail.com

CONTACT

PHONE:

716-555-0100

LINKEDIN:

www.linkedin.com/in/j.mclaughin

EMAIL address

popstar0126@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I'm an experienced software engineer who has 7 years of experience in web development. I can be responsible for the overall development and implementation of front-end and back-end software applications. I prefer the modern JavaScript frameworks and Amazon Web Services. In most projects so far, I used to implement all features including the CI/CD by using these stacks.

In recent projects, I used to build the frontend using React/Typescript and backend using AWS serverless framework based on NodeJS. I have enough experience to work as a full-stack, front-end, cloud engineer. I'm always sensitive to modern technologies and always like learning and sharing ideas with team members. Building state-of-the-art, easy-to-use, user-friendly websites and applications is truly a passion of mine and I'm confident I would be an excellent addition to your organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Full Stack Engineer

FreeCast Inc

Oct 2019 - Sep 2022 (3 years)

Responsible for building complete, high-performance web applications.

- Designed, developed, and modified 25+ software systems and custom components
- Developed the ChatAI with GhatGPT
- Developed useful and simplify Video Streaming Web Platform
- Perform the most complex product technical design and prototyping, software development, bug verification and resolution.
- Designed event-driven architecture with AWS lambda, AWS SQS and AWS SNS
- API development (RESTful, GraphQL) with NodeJS
- Built the Microservices with Golang/Java and Installed them into Docker Containers
- Configured AWS serverless architecture with NodeJS runtime Lambda functions.
- API integration and front-end development with ReactJS
- Unit testing using frameworks like Mocha, Jest, Jasmine, Karma, Cypress, Selenium
- Implemented the CI/CD and automation using GitHub and AWS Services
- Worked with MySQL, PostgreSQL as well as NoSQL databases like MongoDB, AWS DynamoDB
- Took part in development of SaaS application
- UI development with React, Next, Vue from the design such as Figma, Adobe XD
- Worked with Material UI, Semantic UI, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Sass, Less,
- Worked with Jira, Trello, Agile Scrum methodology

Front End Engineer

Darnstown, Maryland, US

Jan 2016 – June 2019 (6 years)

- Took part in development of the LMS (Learning Management System)
- Front-end development with VueJS, NuxtJS, ReactJS, NextJS, Chakra UI
- Built all the UIs by combining Material UI, Chakra UI, Tailwind CSS
- Back-end development with SpringBoot, .Net, NodeJS, Express, NestJS, Laravel
- Configured AWS serverless architecture with Python and NodeJS runtime lambda functions.
- Implemented the CI/CD and automation using AWS, GitHub and Terraform
- Developed a node is server to validate membership and track digital badges being used, saving the company \$22.5K.
- Reduced average valuation review time by 46%, and saved service providers an average of 84% due to click-fee reductions
- Load-balancing and Auto-Scaling configuration using AWS services
- Worked with relative databases such as MySQL, PostgreSQL
- Worked with JavaScript, Typescript, PHP, Python, SQL, SCSS
- Worked with Agile Scrum methodology

EDUCATION

2010 - 2014 Nanjing University, China Bachelor of Computer Science

SKILLS

- HTML5/CSS3/SCSS/Sass
- JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Python, SQL
- React, Redux, Hook, Gatsby, Next
- Material-UI, Chakra-UI, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS
- Vue, Vuex, Vuetify, Nuxt
- Node, Express, Nest, Laravel
- RESTful API, GraphQL, API integration
- Payment integration (Stripe, PayPal, Plaid)
- Google Cloud Platforms, Firebase
- AWS Web Services, Serverless Framework
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS DynamoDB
- CI/CD and automation (AWS, Terraform)